Scott, Harold, 1892-1965. Papers, 1917-1965 (bMS 160): A Finding Aid.
Scott, Harold, 1892-1965. Papers, 1917-1965.
Andover-Harvard Theological Library, Harvard Divinity School
bMS 160
Scott, Harold, 1892-1965.
5 boxes
Papers of Unitarian minister Harold Scott, including writings, correspondence, radio addresses, church newsletters, and scrapbooks. The papers span 1917-1965.
Access
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Harold Guy Don Scott ( 1892-1965 ) was born in Newport, Vermont. He graduated from Alabama Polytechnic University (now Auburn University) with a BS in 1931 and an MS in 1932. He studied theology at the Iliff School of Theology in Denver, Colorado, and graduated with a ThM in 1935 and a ThD in 1938. He was ordained a Unitarian minister at Old Town, Maine, in 1917. He served parishes in Old Town, Maine ( 1916-1918 ); St. Johnsbury, Vermont ( 1918-1920 ); Cincinnati, Ohio ( 1920-1921 ); Camp Hill, Alabama ( 1926-1932 ); Denver, Colorado ( 1933-1935 ); Fort Collins, Colorado ( 1935-1940 ); Flint, Michigan ( 1940-1945 ); Miami, Florida ( 1945-1946 ); Worcester, Massachusetts ( 1947-1950 ); Salt Lake City, Utah ( 1950-1960 ); Cambridge, Massachusetts ( 1960-1962 ); and Kennebunk, Maine ( 1962-1965 ). During his pastorate at Fort Collins, Colorado, he also served as a sociology instructor at Colorado State College. Scott is also the author of Theological Terms in the Light of Modern Scholarship ( 1944 ) and Our Bible Heritage ( 1958 ).
Organized into the following series:
Series I. Writings
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Radio addresses
Series IV. Church newsletters
Series V. Scrapbooks
This collection is divided into five series. Series I contains writings by Scott, including his theses for his MA and ThD degrees. Series II is correspondence, mainly to his nephew Peter Scott. Series III consists of Scott's typescript radio addresses, arranged chronologically. Many of the addresses are also annotated. Series IV contains church newsletters from the various pastorates held by Scott, arranged chronologically. Series V is a collection of scrapbooks. They include photographs and clippings on Scott.
Related Materials
For audio recordings of Scott's radio addresses, please see bMS 15018.
- The number after the slash in each entry in the following list indicates the box number, and the number in parentheses is the folder number.
- Series I. Writings
  - "Some Aspects of the Social Life of a Cotton Community in Alabama." MS thesis, Alabama Polytechnic Institute, 1932, bMS 160/1 (1)
  - "Prolegomena to the Fourth Gospel and a Commentary on the First Six Chapters of the Fourth Gospel." ThD thesis, Iliff School of Theology, 1938, bMS 160/1 (2)
  - "Excuse Me, Parson," n.d. Typed manuscript of autobiography, 241 pages, bMS 160/1 (3)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1953-1965, bMS 160/2 (1)
- Series III. Radio addresses
  - Radio addresses, 1945, bMS 160/2 (2)
  - Radio addresses, 1946, bMS 160/2 (3-4)
  - Radio addresses, 1947, bMS 160/2 (5)
  - Radio addresses, 1948, bMS 160/2 (6)
  - Radio addresses, 1949, bMS 160/2 (7)
  - Radio addresses, 1951, bMS 160/2 (8)
  - Radio addresses, 1952, bMS 160/2 (9)
  - Radio addresses, 1953, bMS 160/2 (10)
  - Radio addresses, 1954, bMS 160/2 (11)
  - Radio addresses, 1955, bMS 160/2 (12)
  - Radio addresses, 1956, bMS 160/2 (13)
  - Radio addresses, 1957, bMS 160/2 (14)
  - Radio addresses, 1957, bMS 160/3 (1)
  - Radio addresses, 1958, bMS 160/3 (2)
  - Radio addresses, 1959, bMS 160/3 (3-4)
  - Radio addresses, 1960, bMS 160/3 (5-6)
  - Radio addresses, numbers 1-180, with gaps (mimeographed copies), n.d., bMS 160/3 (7)
- Series IV. Church newsletters
  - "The Prospector," 1936-1943, bMS 160/4 (1)
  - "The Prospector," 1943-1945, bMS 160/4 (2)
  - "The Quest," 1946-1947, bMS 160/4 (3)
  - "The Message," 1948-1949, bMS 160/4 (4)
  - "Ram's Horn," 1950-1958, bMS 160/4 (5)
  - "Ram's Horn," 1958-1962, bMS 160/4 (6)
- Series V. Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, 1917-1963, includes newspaper clippings and photographs, bMS 160/5 (1)
  - Scrapbook, 1941-1963, includes newspaper clippings, photographs, booklets, and magazine clippings, bMS 160/5 (2)